<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on Ethernet Notes</title><link>https://XintongWang4869.github.io/ethernet-guide/categories/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on Ethernet Notes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://XintongWang4869.github.io/ethernet-guide/categories/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Ethernet</title><link>https://XintongWang4869.github.io/ethernet-guide/docs/intro_to_ethernet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://XintongWang4869.github.io/ethernet-guide/docs/intro_to_ethernet/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Man is something that shall be overcome. What have you done to overcome him?&amp;rdquo; (Thus Spoke Zarathustra, Nietzsche)
Ethernet plays a crucial role in local area networks (LANs) , by connecting wired networked devices within a limited geographical area.
As you may notice, Ethernet itself does not directly participate in internet connections. Instead, it is a local network technology primarily used to facilitate efficient and secure data exchange between devices like computers and printers, serving as the foundation for larger networks, including data centers and internet infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>The OSI Model</title><link>https://XintongWang4869.github.io/ethernet-guide/docs/intro_to_ethernet/osi-model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://XintongWang4869.github.io/ethernet-guide/docs/intro_to_ethernet/osi-model/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Man is something that shall be overcome. What have you done to overcome him?&amp;rdquo; (Thus Spoke Zarathustra, Nietzsche)
Layers of the OSI Model The Open Systems Interconnection (OSI) reference model is a conceptual framework that divides network operations into seven layers:
OSI Model Application Layer:
Provides ​network services directly to end-user applications, how? User interface Specific rules (protocols) for different apps Data semantics Presentation Layer:
Ensures data sent by one application can be correctly interpreted by another1, and also ensures secure2, and efficient communication3: Data format conversion Data encryption/decryption Data compression Session Layer:</description></item><item><title>The Ethernet Standards</title><link>https://XintongWang4869.github.io/ethernet-guide/docs/intro_to_ethernet/ethernet-standards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://XintongWang4869.github.io/ethernet-guide/docs/intro_to_ethernet/ethernet-standards/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Man is something that shall be overcome. What have you done to overcome him?&amp;rdquo; (Thus Spoke Zarathustra, Nietzsche)
Overview of Ethernet Standards IEEE, short for Institute for Electrical and Electronics Engineers, is an institute that develops standards in many industries, and the Ethernet standards are developed by IEEE-SA, IEEE Standards Association. Today, IEEE 802.3 serves as the standard that defines Ethernet protocols, providing the foundation for modern wired network communications.</description></item><item><title>The Ethernet System</title><link>https://XintongWang4869.github.io/ethernet-guide/docs/intro_to_ethernet/ethernet-systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://XintongWang4869.github.io/ethernet-guide/docs/intro_to_ethernet/ethernet-systems/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Man is something that shall be overcome. What have you done to overcome him?&amp;rdquo; (Thus Spoke Zarathustra, Nietzsche)
Half-Duplex and Full-Duplex Modes Previously, before the emergence of Ethernet switches, half-duplex mode is the typical operation for Ethernet devices.
In half-duplex mode:
Multiple computers communicate over a single Ethernet channel via the CSMA/CD MAC protocol . A station (ie., the networked device) first listens to the channel, and if the channel is idle, the station transmits its data (Ethernet frames).</description></item></channel></rss>